<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | Matt Nguyen]]></title>
  <link href="http://mattnguyen.github.io/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mattnguyen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-25T01:36:09+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mattnguyen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Nguyen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Look Back]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattnguyen.github.io/2014/02/22/dont-look-back/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-22T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattnguyen.github.io/2014/02/22/dont-look-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>There&rsquo;s only one rule to riding a motorbike in Vietnam: Don&rsquo;t look back.</p><footer><strong>Don Ho</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>On my third day in Saigon, I decided to rent a motorbike for the next couple of weeks.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Don directed me to a place off of Nguyen Thi Minh Khai. Like most Vietnamese businesses, the rental shop was also the home and residence of the owners. Typically when renting out to foreigners, shops will demand your passport as a kind of security deposit. Since I&rsquo;m not comfortable giving up my passport for a couple weeks, I opted to give the guy $300 in cash instead.</p>

<div class="center"><iframe src="http://mattnguyen.github.io//instagram.com/p/ky57SblilI/embed/" width="390" height="500" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>


<p>The experience has been good so far. I&rsquo;ve been pretty careful about following the &ldquo;rules&rdquo; to avoid getting pulled over by the cops. Apparently, in the event of a police encounter, you can usually avoid getting your bike towed if you pay the cops off for about 200,000VND. Hopefully this doesn&rsquo;t happen.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a video of me motorbiking the streets at night. There&rsquo;s something immensely satisfying about feeling the cool night&rsquo;s breeze blowing in my face.</p>

<div class="center"><iframe src="http://mattnguyen.github.io//instagram.com/p/ky6PIYlila/embed/" width="390" height="500" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good Morning, Saigon]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattnguyen.github.io/2014/02/19/good-morning-saigon/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattnguyen.github.io/2014/02/19/good-morning-saigon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center"><iframe src="http://mattnguyen.github.io//instagram.com/p/kit9yAliuT/embed/" width="390" height="500" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>


<p>After 15 hours of flying, with a layover at Incheon, I finally made it to Saigon safe and sound at around 10:40pm. The ensuing 24 hours was eventful to say the least.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My uncle, Bob (Cậu Bao in Vietnamese), met me at the airport and we grabbed a cab. The feeling was surreal and dreamlike. I have been thinking about this trip for the last two and a half months. So as we were exiting the airport, I rolled down the window and breathed it all in: dim street lights illuminating unmarked lanes; motorbikes zipping by and honking in passing; the low level chatter and laughter of locals drinking beer on the sidewalk in the background. To say I was excited is an understatement. I was ecstatic and enthralled to be living my dream.</p>

<p>However, first order of business: pho. Of course. Unfortunately I was too delirious and brain dead to take a picture of the meal. It was awesome though. I&rsquo;ll have to come back there again to snag a picture with the location. I&rsquo;m still new to this blogging thing and consequently will have to be more diligent about taking pictures and writing down the places I visit.</p>

<p>Since I refused to sleep on the five hour flight from Seoul to Saigon, I woke up the next morning feeling refreshed and ready to explore.</p>

<div class="left-align left-thumbnail"><iframe src="http://mattnguyen.github.io//instagram.com/p/kldcEblig3/embed/" width="250" height="300" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>


<p></p>

<p>I took a taxi to my uncle&rsquo;s office in district 1, the downtown area of Saigon. Since my iPhone unlock didn&rsquo;t go through on time, I got an international Nokia phone for about $25 and a sim card for $10. This will be useful when I travel to Malaysia, Cambodia, Laos, and Thailand. I spent the rest of the day walking around Ben Thanh Market and the backpacker&rsquo;s area with no real purpose or agenda.</p>

<p>While navigating around the street venders hustling sunglasses, fruit, and lottery tickets, I came up on a nice little place serving bun thit nuong cha gio, which is grilled pork over vermicelli with egg roll served on top of a heaping pile of fresh lettuce and herbs. And the price? <strong>A whopping $2</strong>. I&rsquo;m in heaven!</p>

<div class="left-align"><iframe src="http://mattnguyen.github.io//instagram.com/p/kn_S1olip9/embed/" width="390" height="500" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>




<div class="right-align"><iframe src="http://mattnguyen.github.io//instagram.com/p/kn-8rYFipd/embed/" width="390" height="500" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>


<p>When nighttime arrived, I met up with an old friend, Don Ho, for drinks at some restaurant in downtown. He was accompanied by a friend who just moved from Cambodia to Vietnam. Both of these guys work at venture capital firms, and so we basically talked startups, institional money in Vietnam, and bitcoin for the next couple rounds of brews.</p>

<p>At around 10:30pm, we left the restaurant and headed out to <a href="http://www.lush.vn">Lush</a>, a pretty cool electronic and hip hop dance club with two dancing areas and a garden patio. Tuesday night is ladies night, so admission and drinks are free until midnight for&hellip;wait for it&hellip;ladies. When we arrived, the main dance area was so packed, we had to move to the smaller dancing area where the DJ played hip hop for the night. I&rsquo;m pretty sure people were weirded out by my Bay Area dancing, but whatever. I had a blast :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OK, America. See You in Five Months.]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattnguyen.github.io/2014/02/14/ok-america/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattnguyen.github.io/2014/02/14/ok-america</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It seems like only yesterday when I moved from Austin back to San Francisco for Dev Bootcamp. So much has changed since.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Brief update</h3>

<p>After ten grueling weeks of nonstop, intensive learning, I managed to get hired as a Software Engineer at <a href="http://www.tapjoy.com">Tapjoy</a>. For the last year and a half, I was able to work on a plethora of interesting projects including Tapjoy.com, video and MRAID ad products, and eventually building out and shipping the Events Framework and publisher messages. My teammates have all inspired me in different ways, and I&rsquo;m grateful for all that I&rsquo;ve learned in the short time I&rsquo;ve been with them.</p>

<p>Alas, it is time for me to move on. Not to another company or a different professsion. Rather, I&rsquo;ll be doing some serious traveling around Southeast Asia for the next five months.</p>

<h3>Why quit your job then?</h3>

<p>Mainly because I wanted to get away for awhile. No responsibilities. No rent. No pressure. Just the freedom, craziness, and anxiety that comes with backpacking for an extended period of time. It&rsquo;s going to be awesome.</p>

<h3>What are your travel plans?</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m not really sure. I&rsquo;ll be flying into Saigon, and I will be in Vietnam for a little less than a month. After that I&rsquo;ll be hopping on a plane to Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia for <a href="http://www.futuremusicfestival.asia/2014/">Future Music Festival</a>. After FMF, I&rsquo;ll be working my way up Malaysia to Bangkok, Thailand, where I&rsquo;ll be meeting <a href="http://www.bsiddiqui.com">Basil</a> for Songkran and Full Moon Festival.</p>

<p>When Basil leaves, I&rsquo;ll work my way East to Cambodia, North through Laos, and then back into Vietnam where I&rsquo;ll head south down Vietnam&rsquo;s coast back to Saigon. I have no real plans for this portion of the trip, so it&rsquo;s a little bit unstructured at the moment. But that&rsquo;s what makes this so damn fun :).</p>

<h3>That&rsquo;s about it</h3>

<p>So this is where I&rsquo;m at in my life. I leave in a couple days. I&rsquo;m going to be a little bit more dilligent about blogging this time around. Heck, I even built out and customized my own octopress blog (more info on this in another post) for this purpose. If you want to find out what I&rsquo;m doing, feel free to check back here, follow my <a href="http://instagram.com/__mattn">instagram</a> (@__mattn), or follow my <a href="https://twitter.com/MrMattNguyen">twitter</a> (@mrmattnguyen) for updates.</p>

<p>I plan on following up with more detailed information about my Asia trip, including backpacking essentials, itineraries, must-see places, must-go-to parties, and anything you might want to know if you&rsquo;re considering doing something similar.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s to 2014! Wish me luck!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
