<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life Update | Matt Nguyen]]></title>
  <link href="http://MattNguyen.github.io/blog/categories/life-update/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MattNguyen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T21:27:13-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://MattNguyen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Nguyen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OK, America. See You in Five Months.]]></title>
    <link href="http://MattNguyen.github.io/2014/02/14/ok/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://MattNguyen.github.io/2014/02/14/ok</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It seems like only yesterday when I moved from Austin back to San Francisco for Dev Bootcamp. So much has changed since.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Brief update</h3>

<p>After ten grueling weeks of nonstop, intensive learning, I managed to get hired as a Software Engineer at <a href="http://www.tapjoy.com">Tapjoy</a>. For the last year and a half, I was able to work on a plethora of interesting projects including Tapjoy.com, video and MRAID ad products, and eventually building out and shipping the Events Framework and publisher messages. My teammates have all inspired me in different ways, and I&rsquo;m grateful for all that I&rsquo;ve learned in the short time I&rsquo;ve been with them.</p>

<p>Alas, it is time for me to move on. Not to another company or a different professsion. Rather, I&rsquo;ll be doing some serious traveling around Southeast Asia for the next five months.</p>

<h3>Why quit your job then?</h3>

<p>Mainly because I wanted to get away for awhile. No responsibilities. No rent. No pressure. Just the freedom, craziness, and anxiety that comes with backpacking for an extended period of time. It&rsquo;s going to be awesome.</p>

<h3>What are your travel plans?</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m not really sure. I&rsquo;ll be flying into Saigon, and I will be in Vietnam for a little less than a month. After that I&rsquo;ll be hopping on a plane to Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia for <a href="http://www.futuremusicfestival.asia/2014/">Future Music Festival</a>. After FMF, I&rsquo;ll be working my way up Malaysia to Bangkok, Thailand, where I&rsquo;ll be meeting <a href="http://www.bsiddiqui.com">Basil</a> for Songkran and Full Moon Festival.</p>

<p>When Basil leaves, I&rsquo;ll work my way East to Cambodia, North through Laos, and then back into Vietnam where I&rsquo;ll work my way South down the coast back to Saigon. I have no real plans for this portion of the trip, so it&rsquo;s a little bit unstructured at the moment. But that&rsquo;s what makes this so damn fun :).</p>

<h3>That&rsquo;s about it</h3>

<p>So this is where I&rsquo;m at in my life. I leave in a couple days. I&rsquo;m going to be a little bit more dilligent about blogging this time around. Heck, I even built out and customized my own octopress blog for this purpose. If you want to find out what I&rsquo;m doing, feel free to check back here, follow my <a href="http://instagram.com/mnguyen916">instagram</a> (@mnguyen916), or follow my <a href="https://twitter.com/MrMattNguyen">twitter</a> (@mrmattnguyen) for updates.</p>

<p>I plan on following up with more detailed information about my Asia trip, including backpacking essentials, itineraries, must-see places, must-go-to parties, and anything you might want to know if you&rsquo;re considering doing something similar.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s to 2014! Wish me luck!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Life and Moving Forward]]></title>
    <link href="http://MattNguyen.github.io/2012/05/13/on-life-and-moving-forward/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MattNguyen.github.io/2012/05/13/on-life-and-moving-forward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="font-style: italic;"><a href="http://matt-nguyen.tumblr.com/post/22890572560/on-life-and-moving-forward">(This Tumblr post</a> has been reposted to provide some continuity for my new site and life journey.)</p>


<p>For my inaugural Tumblr post, I feel obligated to update those who are close to me on what I have been doing, what I will be doing, and why I created this <strike>Tumblr account</strike>.</p>


<p>(TL;DR - I've been living in Austin as a project manager for the last year; I'm moving back to the Bay to do Dev Bootcamp and will forgo law school; I'm documenting my journey to inspire those who are considering the same path)</p>


<!-- more -->


<p><strong>What I've been doing</strong></p>


<p>After graduating from Cal in winter 2010, I moved to Southern California to work for <a href="http://www.gettrx.com">Global Electronic Technology Inc.</a>, a merchant services company specializing in payment processing solutions, with my degree in rhetoric in one hand and a suitcase full of clothes in the other. The plan was simple: I would take the next year and a half to develop my professional skills while preparing for law school. The job would be a stepping stone on my journey towards lawyerhood and served two purposes: one, since the company was moving to Austin, TX, relocating would strategically position me in the middle of the country where I could easily mobilize myself in the event I were accepted to a prominent law school on either coasts; and two, I would delay the inevitable soul crushing proffered by three years of intense legal studies.</p>


<p>Almost a year has passed since moving to Austin, and I am fairly certain that attending law school now will be a bad choice for a plethora of reasons, many of which were derived from reading through&nbsp;<a href="http://top-law-schools.com/forums/index.php">this law school forum</a>&nbsp;( an&nbsp;amazing resource for prospective law students). Although GET has been a great company to work for, I yearned to step out of my comfort zone and challenge myself with computer science and web development. I began reading free online resources and participated in online courses, such as <a href="http://www.coursera.com">Coursera</a>, <a href="http://www.codeacademy.com">Codeacademy</a>, and <a href="http://www.udacity.com">Udacity</a>. After reading several blogs about learning strategies for computer science, I came across <a href="http://www.devbootcamp.com">Dev Bootcamp</a>, a 10-week intensive Ruby on Rails program dedicated to turning individuals with no programming experience into "world class beginners." I applied, interviewed with <a href="http://tedxtalks.ted.com/video/TEDxSF-Shereef-Bishay-Open-Ente">Shereef Bishay</a>, received my acceptance, and submitted my deposit not too long after discovering this wonderful program (future post on the DBC application process forthcoming).</p>


<p><strong>What I'm going to do</strong></p>


<p>I am pretty damn excited about this, and it's hard not to be considering recent praise over <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/10/dev-boot-camp-is-a-ruby-success/">DBC's first cohort's employment results</a>. With 88% of the class receiving offers of $79k on average, becoming a web developer makes more economic and financial sense than attending law school, where <a href="http://insidethelawschoolscam.blogspot.com/2012/03/career-opportunities.html">recent graduates are struggling to find jobs</a>, are completely overwhelmed with <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/law/2012/05/07/projected-law-school-debt-figures-revised-even-higher/">six figures of non-dischargeable debt</a>, and are seeking <a href="http://abovethelaw.com/2012/02/twelve-more-law-schools-slapped-with-class-action-lawsuits-over-employment-data/">legal recourse against schools</a> who misrepresent employment statistics. From June 11 to &nbsp;August 17, I will be sharing an office space with approximately 40 other motivated students who are just as eager to learn RoR and launch their new careers as web developers. Already, the level of collaboration is high with students attending meet-ups and hack nights together, and the program hasn't even started! It will be interesting to see what we'll be able to accomplish at the end of the 10 weeks.&nbsp;</p>


<p><strong>Why I created this blog</strong></p>


<p>From being a prospective law student to becoming a web developer, I am compelled to document my story so that future generations of Booters can benefit from my experiences, and hopefully I can inspire people with non-technical backgrounds who are passionate about technology and motivated to switch careers to take the plunge and do something about it. I have not completely given up my aspiration for attending law school, but I have not found compelling reasons to do so right now. Perhaps when a future opportunity presents itself, I'll attend law school for intellectual property law *cough*Stanford*cough*Boalt*&nbsp;since I'll be in a much better position to do so as a web developer. In any case, I'm thrilled for this opportunity, and I absolutely cannot wait to see my friends, family, and meet my fellow Booters in the Bay.&nbsp;</p>


<p></p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
